No!
"My name is Kudō Shin'ichi."
"I'm a famous high school student detective."
"However, one day when I visited an amusement park, with my childhood
friend Ran..."
"...where I witnessed two men in black being involved in a shady deal."
"And they poisoned me using a drug known as "APTX 4869".
"Then when I came to..."
"...my body had been shrunken."
"If the word has it that, I, Kudō Shin'ichi was still alive..."
"...the Black Organization could bring danger
to all those around me."
"Under the alias of Edogawa Conan..."
"...I solve countless cases while trying to obtain intel about the men in black who shrunk my body."
"But this is a case that occurred 100 days
before I became Edogawa Conan."
"While taking a trip with Ran and the rest,
we came across a village's legend..."
"...and became involved in
an impossible murder case."
"Mysterious murders in a row..."
"...and I, too, faced setback by an unexpected trick."
Wait up!
A rumor about the high school student
who's a great detective has appeared.
You've solved a murder case
once again, haven't you?
This time around it was a locked room case,
so how did you figure out who the murderer was?
Teitan
High School
You were brilliant this time too, weren't you?
What were your feelings when the police detectives
found themselves in over their heads as you solved it?
Ah, let's see...
"Yes, this is me..."
Kudō Shin'ichi
"...the high school student detective,
Kudō Shin'ichi."
"Of course at the time I couldn't
have even imagined that, in the near future..."
"...I'd be returning here
as a grade school student."
Well, somehow or other...
- Kudō-san.
- One word, please.
Oi!
Ha!
That was dangerous!
"She's Mōri Ran..."
"...my childhood friend."
"Deep down she's a good gal,
but she's also strong in karate."
"We aren't dating though."
Anyhow, break out, break out!
Itadakimasu!
Please don't feel reserved
and eat as much as you'd like.
Ran, you've been so worried about your figure,
that you haven't been eating at all.
You don't have to actively
compete anymore, you know.
Mom, that's not true.
Thank you very much.
I'll eat heartily.
Yeah, go ahead.
Well? Any good?
"It's awful!"
I've been worried about my figure as well.
It itches. Ah!
Mom, what's the matter?
Recently, when someone tells a lie...
...my left eye starts to itch.
Eh?
Well, I run into so many
incidents of it as a lawyer...
...but it bothers me most when
my clients start lying.
Because of that,
my eye's gotten very sensitive to lies.
It's my predisposition towards
cause and effect.
Ah, it's kind of an occupational disease.
"This person is Kisaki Eri."
"She's a shrewd lawyer who never
loses a case and she's Ran's mother."
"However she and Eri's father, Mōri Kogoro,
are separated, pending their divorce."
And? Shin'ichi-kun,
what were you lying about just now?
Eh?
"Bad cook"
Ah, Mom, we have a guest.
Eh? Who could that be?
Sonoko!
Ran, I've come.
Hello, Kudō-kun.
Popular as ever, aren't you?
I saw you on TV.
"This stuff's awful!
I don't want this."
I'm not happy about it.
I just want to go home.
Then I'm just in time.
Say, it's awfully sudden...
...but how about we all go to Jyugoya Village?
(Jyugoya - Night of the full moon)
"This is Suzuki Sonoko..."
"...the daughter of the Suzuki Financial clique."
"She's one of Japan's richest people,
but she's sociable and follows the latest fads."
"She's always inviting us to wherever
various incidents have occurred."
Jyugoya Village?
A friend of Papa's built a villa there
and he's invited me to come visit at any time.
Could it be
this friend of your father's is...
Bingo!
Japan's biggest chain of taverns
that you're the legal adviser for...
"Wakura Group’s President Wakura!
Uncle Wakura said he
wants you to come, no matter what.
If Wakura-san is asking...
...can't turn him down, now can I?
- All right!
Ah!
Huh?
What about Dad?
I don't want that person going with us.
Rascal!
Ras...
I told you, it's "Pascal."
That's so ambiguous...
Normally a raccoon's named Rascal.
Ours is far more clever
than any 'Rascal' would be.
Ala?
Ala, I just heard some sound.
It might be Pascal!
Please go take a look.
Eh?
You... want me to go up there?
"Acrophobia"
Eh? You won't go up?
Then I won't pay you.
I only came because you said
there was a kidnapping.
Why is this happening to me...
Ah, did you say something just now?
No, no, no.
Oh! There, wai...
Wait, wai...
"By the way, this old man
is Ran's father, Mōri Kogoro."
"He left the police
and opened a detective agency..."
"...but as for his ability..."
"...well, how can I put this..."
Anyhow, we decided to leave him behind
and go to Jyugoya Village.
Pascal!
"Northeast Bus Stop
Jyugoya Village"
Whaa, we arrived at last.
But why are you still
in your school uniform?
Couldn't help it.
I couldn't go home, after all.
Uncle Wakura, it's been awhile!
Yes... Welcome.
"Wakura" Group President
Wakura Isamu"
- Hello.
- It's been awhile.
Who is this?
Ah, my daughter.
This is my friend, Mōri Ran-san...
...and the famous high school
student detective, Kudō Shin'ichi.
- Hello.
A detective?
Wakura-san, we're sorry for
forcing ourselves upon you like this today.
Not at all, not at all.
It's an honor to have Sensei come.
Welcome to the village of the legendary Otori.
(Otori - Large Bird)
"Village of the legendary Otori"?
In this village a long time ago...
...legend has it that a huge Mozu appeared,
attacking the villagers...
...and making them what is called a hayanie.
Hayanie?
A Mozu catches insects and frogs...
(Mozu - 'butcher bird' or shrike)
...and has the trait of
stabbing them on tree branches.
Those are the Mozu's hayanie.
It's characteristic is to stick them on
sharp objects like barbed wire and twigs.
Ah, there, there.
There's one.
Eh? Auntie, that surprised me!
Geez, Dad, don't shock them
like that anymore.
"Wakura's Second Daughter
Wakura Misa"
I'm sorry... How do you do,
I'm his daughter Misa.
Wakura-san is helping us
investigate the Otori legend. I'm Kozaka.
"Graduate Student
Kozaka Sho"
We'll be under your care.
I got caught up in
the Otori legend just now. Excuse me.
Come, let's go.
Yes.
"Jyugoya Village"
This is a beautiful place, isn't it?
But, scary!
Still, the only access to
the village is across this bridge.
So do your best for a little longer.
- Yes.
- Yes!
- Hey, Ran!
- Sorry!
Why did you come in
those sorts of shoes for?
You should have brought some
that were more for walking.
You don't understand, Shin'ichi-kun.
At her age, the emphasis is
more on appearance than practicality.
Appearance? Who's going to be
looking at you here in the mountains?
See, you totally don't get it.
It's okay. I like them.
If you fall, you'll definitely die.
Hey! Hey there!
Shin'ichi, stop it! You're the lowest!
Stop it, you guys!
That's dangerous!
It's slippery through here,
so please be careful.
Because you're a guy, you go first.
Don't push! That's dangerous. All right, I'll go.
"Mozutobi Shrine" (Flying Mozu Shrine)
You guys are women
and yet way too over strong.
What's that?!
What are the characteristics of
the village's Otori legend?
It's very similar to the legend of Forbina
left behind by the Mayan civilization.
Ever since my school days...
...I've been chasing cases across the globe
of legendary monstrous birds like the Otori.
Because there's a possibility...
...there remains in this village
something transmitted from...
...the ancient Mayan civilization to Japan.
It could lead to a tremendous discovery.
What is that?
People of the village call it, "God's Perch."
"Mozutobi Shrine
God's Perch"
This was the place where
sacrifices were made to Otori-sama.
Sacrifices?
Yes.
One would be chosen as a hayanie
and be sacrificed here.
It's said that Otori-sama's anger...
...would thus be dispelled and that famine and
catastrophe would hopefully not occur.
There are others like this
here and there around the village.
Good afternoon.
Ah, good afternoon.
Ah, you have guests?
Yes.
It's great we have
such fine weather, isn't it?
Do you as the police
have business at the shrine, too?
Yes.
I was pressed into helping with
the preparations for the festival.
Uncle, is there a festival?
3 days from now.
What kind of festival is it?
Ah, here at the Mozutobi Shrine,
there's to be a festival to Otori-sama.
In order to calm
Otori-sama's turbulent soul...
...they'll be dressed as birds
and chant prayers while dancing.
But, for this year only,
this one will be special.
Right, Mr. Policeman?
Ah, that's right.
A bronze mirror, which is a national treasure
that can only be viewed once every 300 years...
...will be here at the inner shrine.
The festival 3 days from now
only comes once every 300 years.
Are you serious?!
Once every 300 years?
We're super lucky, aren't we?
We get to see a hidden mirror in an unexplored area.
Note: Both words are pronounced the same.
Hikyou
(hidden mirror)
(An unexplored area)
Eh?
Hikyou?
Note: Ran doesn't get the other meaning of 'hikyou'
It means "secret mirror."
Don't make me explain my puns.
Sorry.
But, it really is a secret mirror.
Legend has it that when the bronze mirror
resonates with the God's Perch...
...mysterious things occur.
What mysterious things?
According to the ancient literature...
...something very much like
a total solar eclipse.
A total solar eclipse?
But, I'm sure the next time one of those
will be seen in Japan won't be until 2035.
Ridiculous, isn't it?
But, believers have their dreams.
Most of the people in the village
think what will happen is they'll be cursed...
...and it seems they're getting
a little nervous.
Um... Because it's so long-awaited,
really, please stay here until the festival.
"Mozutobi Shrine"
Didn't you listen to what I just told you?
Dad!
Dad, are you okay?
"Wakura's Eldest Son
Wakura Yoichi"
"Wakura's Eldest Daughter
Wakura Kotomi"
Say, what caused this to happen?
"Wakura's Second Son
Wakura Ryoji"
It's incomprehensible.
While all of us were
walking around and chatting...
...we thought we heard a bird cry.
Then suddenly, Kozaka-san...
It's true! We then realized Kozaka-san
had been stuck up there!
It's regrettable that I'm the one still safe.
What are you saying?
Dad!
Dad.
What's the matter?
Are you in pain?
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
Wakura-san.
That truly is regrettable.
Ryoji-niisan!
Kudō-kun!
Kudō-kun, isn't it?
"This person is Megure Juzo."
"He's Ran's father's former boss."
"He's called the 'Demon Capitan of the MPD...'"
"...but truth is, he's also a devoted husband."
What are you doing at a place like this for?
I was invited by Sonoko to come
to a villa here in this village.
Captain Megure, what are you doing here?
Well, I had come to train
the police in this prefecture...
...so when they said a murder case had occurred,
I came to help out in the investigation.
This is Otori-sama's curse!
The people being attacked are its hayanie...
...it's the legendary Otori coming true!
Drawn in by the
once-every-300 years festival...
...and because of the Wakura clan's selfish
investigation into and excavation of the ruins...
...Otori-sama has been angered!
It's as the storyteller says!
That's right, it's the curse!
The curse!
Who's the old lady?
She seems to be called "the storyteller."
She's the one who manages the shrine here.
Ah... This investigation will be difficult.
Eh...
In order that we may investigate the corpse,
he will be taken down to the village.
Because we'll be listening to
the circumstances of each of you in turn...
...please, none of you leave the village.
Since the crime scene must be preserved...
...definitely don't meddle around here.
Yes!
You are? Let's see...
Ah! Policeman Haji at your service!
Nice to be working with you.
Yes, sir!
"People can't die from a legend."
"This is..."
"...a case of murder."
"This impossible murder mystery..."
"I will solve it!"
Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
Detective Conan
Commemorating the 15th Anniversary
Kudō Shin'ichi:
Mizobata Jyunpei
Mōri Ran:
Kutsuna Shiori
Suzuki Sonoko:
Akimoto Sayaka (of AKB48)
Megure Juzo:
Itake Masato
Kisaki Eri:
Otsuka Nene
Mōri Kogoro:
Jinnai Takanori
Detective Conan Drama Special
Challenge to Kudō Shin'ichi
Riddle of the Mysterious Legendary Bird
"Wakura Family Villa"
Well, well, well... sorry for being late.
That voice is...
Oh, Bret Nelli, where is your house?
Everyone, are you excited?
Dad...
Whaa... What did he come for?
Oh, oh?
The conversation doesn't seem to be
as lively as I had imagined.
As I thought, you can't fill in the void
when you're missing a detective.
I'll show you that when it comes to the art of
talking mysteries, you have a long ways to go!
Time for the bad man.
Is that right...
This is a murder case.
Hmm, most regrettable.
If this detective, Mōri Kogoro,
had come just a little earlier...
...like that, I would have caught the culprit.
What are you talking about?
If the culprit was stupid enough
to be caught by you...
...Shin'ichi-kun would have
caught him ages ago.
When it comes to detective work, he's my pupil.
I taught him everything.
Ah, itchy, itchy!
- Here you are.
- Thank you for this.
At any rate, your father
seems to be a huge bird lover.
Birds, here, there and everywhere.
My father is serious about
investigating the Otori legend.
It's amazing how passionate he is
in buying up all the land in the village.
Excuse me.
Look carefully; that's a hot guy.
Sonoko, that's imprudent at a time like this.
Now that I, the great detective
Mōri Kogoro have come...
...this case is as good as solved already.
Please tell your father, "be at ease."
Ah, itchy!
If I could have an aperitif, my head would
become increasingly clearer.
Ah, so itchy!
Geez!
Ah, delicious!
As way of saying thanks...
...I, the great detective Mōri Kogoro,
will settle this incident perfectly.
Truth is, I have already...
...determined the culprit's objective.
Who's the culprit?
The culprit is...
The culprit is?
A human!
Everyone...
...this Otori legend is simply a superstition.
In this 21st century, for educated adults
to be misled by a superstition...
...is absolutely disgraceful.
Eh?
Dad, that's it?
Yeah.
Don't you have a concrete idea
about who the suspect is?
Nope!
Excuse me a minute.
Otori legend, huh?
Aren't such things in many cases told
in order to protect a treasure from looters?
Huh? Huh? Huh?
Do you mean that...
...there's a real treasure
buried in this village?
You just want to look for the
Tokigawa buried treasure, don't you?
(famed lost treasure)
The Tokigawa buried treasure!
A man's romance!
What man's romance?
The Tokigawa buried treasure, huh?
How should I declare it on my tax returns?
There is a romantic legend about this village.
Eh? What is it? Please tell us.
That lovers who exchange kisses
beneath the God's Perch...
...will never be parted and be married for life.
Kiss...
It's a legend only girls
would feel like believing in.
Ran, you should give it a test!
I won't test that!
"Something called Otori that's attacking
village people and making them its hayanie."
"And a legend of a kiss in this village."
"There's a fairly wide mismatch here."
Um, earlier at the scene of the crime,
I picked this up.
These carvings...
I wonder if they're characters?
They're similar to the characters
used at the Fobina ruins.
If I'm certain, this means "curse."
"Curse"?
Would you know what this piece is?
Dad?
Dad?!
Wakura-san?! Wakura-san!
Are you okay?
What is this?
What's going on?
What's happening?
What is this?
What on earth is this!
Dad! Are you alright?
Wakura-san! Wakura-san!
Uncle, are you okay?
Dad, hang in there.
Hey! Shin'ichi!
Damn!
How'd it go?
This just struck so suddenly.
What on earth happened?!
Ala? Where's Wakura-san?
It was a power outage.
What are you so worked up over?
Well, it wasn't about that!
A bird-man suddenly appeared and...
Yoichi-san.
Your father had a spasm and Ryoji-san
and the others attended him back to his room.
My father had a... what?
His room...?
Didn't you call an ambulance?
Well that's...
An ambulance would be
exaggerating things.
Having him examined by some country hospital
would be pointless.
If his condition's still bad in the morning...
...we'll take him to Tokyo
to be examined there.
Yeah.
Will he really be okay like that?
If he does die in the village of the
legendary Otori that he loves so much...
...he'd be satisfied, wouldn't he?
Onee-san!
I'm joking.
Yoichi-san.
Just where did you go?
Where?
I was having a smoke in my room.
This.
"Upon the entire Wakura family..."
"...who fouls our sacred precinct..."
"...we place a curse to be killed."
"Curse"
"Killed"
"The culprit most likely deliberately
placed this piece at the crime scene..."
"...in order to bring out Wakura-san's spasm
when he saw this 'curse' character."
"And clearly, this is a character
and a portion of a picture."
"If my inference is correct..."
"...when the pieces are put back together..."
"...the culprit's true motives will appear."
Oi!
"Ruins
God's Perch"
Where are you?
Calling me out in the
middle of the night like this.
Is this about the distribution of the property?
Ala?
That sound.
The paper the threatening letter
is on has no characteristics about it.
It's commonly used in newspapers.
Whoever issued this threatening letter,
we won't find out from this.
We have no choice but to send it to forensics
and let them investigate it.
Oi!
There's a detective here, so listen up.
Ah...
The Wakura chain has 4,000 branches
across the country.
10,000 employees.
Well, given only just those,
some incident is bound to occur every day.
If I could solve this one case here
and that became well-known...
...I could be employed by them
as a special-adviser detective.
The Special Adviser Detective,
Mōri Kogoro is born!
I'll collect consultant fees
each and every month!
Eh?
Seriously!?
So fast...
Somehow, I couldn't sleep.
Ah.
Because something like that happened...
...will the festival be canceled?
Maybe.
But, it only comes 1 day every 300 years.
Once every 300 years, huh?
Shin'ichi, do you think a total solar eclipse
will really happen?
A total eclipse would be impossible.
Still, I am a little interested in
what might happen.
Hmm...
Is being a little interested all there is?
Eh?
Look, um, well...
...there's that romantic story, too,
isn't there?
What was that?
Nothing!
What is it?
What are you so angry about?
"That lovers who exchange kisses
beneath the God's Perch..."
"...will never be parted
and be married for life."
"Kiss..."
To the edge of the light, calm down...
Ryoji-san!
Anyhow, we need to inform Inspector Megure.
It's no good. Like I thought,
cell phones can't get through here.
- Please do.
- Yes.
Calm down!
"Another one."
"Like I thought..."
"...the culprit is leaving one
at each of his killing sites."
The light...
"When I seriously consider the situation..."
"...he couldn't have been killed
by being stabbed."
"So how did the culprit
get Ryoji-san up there..."
"Moreover, just what on earth
was that sound...?"
To the edge of the light, calm down.
Shin'ichi.
The phones weren't working...
...and my father and the others
are investigating the cause right now.
What was that?
Don't tell me!
Wait, Shin'ichi!
Ran!
Are you okay?
Yeah.
No way...
We were too late.
Shin'ichi?
The bridge didn't fall on its own.
The culprit cut it down.
How did you know this would happen?
When you told me
the phones weren't working...
...I realized the culprit was trying to
confine us here to this village.
Until all of his serial killings are over.
"All"? You mean there'll be more?
Yeah.
Until this piece is complete.
Ryoji-niisan! Niisan!
Niisan!
What is this?
Then we can't leave this village?
No!
The walkie-talkies at the police station
are also broken...
...and the phones can't be used, either...
The walkie-talkies, too?
This is Otori-sama's curse.
Otori-sama has gotten angry!
Now, hurry and leave this village!
That's right! Get out right now!
Don't make Otori-sama any angrier!
Get out!
Please calm down a little.
Because we'll figure how to
repair the bridge and phones...
...please return to your homes for now.
For now, just in case,
please stay in groups...
...and don't let yourselves
end up alone. Please.
The suspension bridge to the other side
from the village has collapsed, huh?
Yeah.
That means the culprit let
the suspension bridge from the village fall.
- In other words...
- Yes.
The culprit is still in the village.
Who will be next?
Who will it be?
It's in accordance with the threatening letter.
Most likely the next one will be...
Me or Yoichi-niisan...
...or maybe you, Misa.
We finished dinner at 9 pm.
At that time,
Ryoji-san was still here in the villa.
Everyone saw that.
Ran and I went out for a walk
and found his corpse at 11 pm.
For those 2 hours between 9 pm and 11 pm...
...everyone please confirm their alibis.
Alibi...
One of us killed Ryoji?
Yoichi-san.
If you told us, would that cause
some sort of trouble for you?
Ridiculous!
Until 10 pm, I was with Ran
and her mother talking...
...but after that I went to sleep.
I don't have an alibi.
I was just in my room.
It was the same for
Yoichi-niisan and Misa, wasn't it?
But...
...there's our father, too.
He has no alibi.
This is...
Shin'ichi, do you understand what this means?
If I'm not mistaken, this is "betrayal."
This is "curse."
What is this man doing?
Is he running?
What sort of meaning...
...is there to this picture?
Ah, delicious!
Misa-san, this was freshly-squeezed, wasn't it?
I'm a man who can tell the difference.
It's just from a regular carton of milk.
Geez... (mou...)
"Moo"? Was that a pun?
That was a pun, right?
Everyone.
You don't seem to have much of an appetite.
Ryoji-san and Kozaka-san's murderer
hasn't been caught.
The phones aren't working and the
suspension bridge has been felled.
The walkie-talkies at
the police station are broken.
Well, if those were our only concerns,
this wouldn't be impossible.
But please everyone, don't worry.
The name that resound around the world,
Mōri Kogoro, is luckily right here.
Just where in the world does it resound?
Does your world have a radius of 1 meter?
Shut up with your complaints
about the little things!
Ah! It's only 50 cm! Excuse me.
There's something I'd like to ask all of you.
Was there anyone who bore
a grudge against Ryoji-san?
Dunno...
He did a lot of things, but I don't think
he made any enemies who'd want to kill him.
But, he was in debt, wasn't he?
In debt?
Yes.
Ryoji was managing a restaurant
separate from the Wakura chain...
...but it wasn't going well.
I don't know what the amount
of his debts were, though.
Is that right?
By the way, what sort of work
do you do, Yoichi-san?
Right now I'm raising funds to start
a business making earnings from stocks.
"Raising funds"?
Yoichi-niisan's only wanted pocket money
so he could make tiny trades over the Internet.
Moreover, just the other day
you secretly went to Dad...
...crying about how you'd
suffered a huge loss in FX.
That's better than some dull guy
who has to be financially supported.
I heard your boyfriend's a musician
who hasn't even sold a song.
What was that?!
Stop it, both of you.
Geez!
What's with this messed-up questioning?!
You've got a long ways to go
before you're a detective.
Green. Too young.
I already know who the culprit is.
Who is the culprit?
The culprit is...
The culprit is?
...you, Yoichi-san.
Eh? Me?
This unusual cigarette is yours, isn't it?
I clearly saw you smoking one yesterday.
And I discovered this one at the site
where Ryoji-san was murdered.
This great detective's eagle eye
doesn't miss anything!
Give me a break! Just because I smoke
doesn't make me the murderer!
Jerk! Do you intend to deny it! You bug!
I wonder if it is.
Even if we agreed that Yoichi-san went
to the scene and left a cigarette butt...
...you're stretching things a bit, aren't you?
Huh?
These butts were carelessly left
in every ashtray in the house.
That means anyone who came into the house
would have been able to take one.
So this one doesn't mean anything.
Ah! Hey, hey!
You idiot!
This is important evidence!
I heard it was a serious loss.
Well, but... Kozaka-san and Ryoji's death
would really make Yoichi-niisan happy though.
What are you saying?
That'd be you Kotomi, wouldn't it?!
Please, stop it.
Um... Excuse me as well.
I'll go see to my father.
I have a favor to ask.
Could you keep an eye on Kotomi-san?
All right.
And Sonoko, on Yoichi-san.
What about you, Shin'ichi?
I'll...
...be on Misa-san.
How is he?
He seems to be sleeping well.
I see.
I wonder when the
suspension bridge will be restored?
I want to take him to the hospital right away.
Kudō-kun, please.
Hurry and catch the culprit.
Yes.
Misa-san...
...could I ask you a question?
Kotomi-san mentioned this earlier.
That if Kozaka-san and Ryoji-san were dead,
Yoichi-san would be happy.
What did she mean by that?
Misa-san.
When my father declared he would invest his
entire fortune into investigating the Otori legend...
...my older brothers and sister
were opposed to it.
At the time, my father told us...
"Kozaka-kun should have been my son."
"I have no intention of leaving
any of you my assets."
"Kozaka-kun would use it more effectively."
It seems that came as a great shock
to my brothers and sister.
Yoichi-niisan definitely seems to be in debt.
But, that's also why it'd be impossible for him to
do anything to either Kozaka-san or Ryoji-niisan.
Give me a break.
Won't you stop this play and wake up?
I'm sure my sister wouldn't have
any reason to, either.
However...
...after my father became
engrossed in the Otori legend...
...it became awkward around the house.
"I will tell you how to
monopolize the inheritance."
"Come to Jyugoya Falls'
God's Perch at 3 o'clock."
Thinking about how it might happen again...
...worries and worries me.
Surely it wouldn't come to this?
Thank you.
The God's Perch is about 6 meters tall.
Both Kozaka-san and Ryoji-san...
...weighed a little more
than 60 kg each, I think.
How did the culprit...
...stick them up there at that height?
That is accursed!
What are you doing?
Do you want to be the fourth person
to become a hayanie?
Fourth person?
What do you mean
when you say 'the fourth person.'?
Who other than Kozaka-san
and Ryoji-san were taken as hayanie?
It's best not to wander around
the holy place without good reason.
Please tell me!
Who was it...
...and when did they become a hayanie?!
- Don't know.
- Please tell me!
I said I don't know, so I don't know!
Please! Please tell me!
The culprit is still...
They're definitely still in this village!
This isn't the deed of a human.
It's Otori-sama's curse.
The Wakura clan set off Otori-sama's anger...
...and so it made them hayanie.
The festival will be soon.
What's more, the total solar eclipse
that only happens once every 300 years.
Otori-sama will certainly appear.
Shin'ichi!
What's happened?
Sorry. When I took my eyes off her
for just a minute, Kotomi-san disappeared
Over there!
Kotomi-san, are you okay?
Ah, what the...
I was just a little surprised.
Jyugoya Falls
God's Perch
Thank goodness nothing happened.
Oh, Otori.
To the edge of the light, calm down.
Shin'ichi?! Kotomi-san!
Shin'ichi!
Kudō-kun! Kudō-kun!
Ow...
Are you okay?
- Somehow or other.
- Thank goodness.
Kotomi-san, are you hurt?
No. I'm really very sorry.
I felt this sudden sensation
and then I flew...
Flew?
What on earth is going on?
What, what is it?
Ala? Where's Ran?
She was running off in that direction.
Ran!
Ow...
Ah... Ran.
Sir?
Ran!
Ran! Are you okay, Ran!
Are you okay? Are you hurt?
Shin'ichi...
I'm fine.
Ah... geez.
But, when I kicked the culprit's
right hand, something flew out.
Ran...
...why did you do something
so reckless on your own for?
Sorry.
Sir! Sir! Sir!
Dad, what are you doing here?
Dad!
What is this?
Making us worry.
I really don't believe this.
It's wet.
No way.
Yuck, I'm drenched! Why?
It's been clear all day today.
Don't catch cold.
Thank you.
But then you'll feel cold, Shin'ichi.
Oh, I'm fine.
Thank goodness I'm not alone.
Shin'ichi's here with me.
It's pitiful I'm just stuck here
and can't rescue you.
That's not true.
I'm happy that we came.
But...
...even if it hadn't been me...
...you would have gone out
to rescue anyone, wouldn't you?
I...
Did you see that just now? A raccoon dog!
Ah... Huh?!
Huh? A raccoon?!
Dad, are you alright?
You said raccoon just now.
Sir?
Wh... where'd it go?
If I can catch that raccoon,
I can substitute it for Pascal.
Are you still asleep?
What's this 'substitute Pascal' talk?
Raccoons are usually called Rascal, aren't they?
This one's a Pascal!
Anyhow, I was chasing after this raccoon
and I ended up down here...
Get ahold of yourself, Dad!
Pascal...
What about Pascal?
The French philosopher and physicist.
Pascal's law is the basis for fluid dynamics...
Mom!
Ma'am!
Are you okay?
Oi! Hurry and do something about this!
Say, what are YOU doing down there?
Ran's an adult already...
...so if you bother her anymore,
she'll hate you.
Anyhow, this was those two's
big chance, right, you two?
- It wasn't like that!
Itchy, itchy, itchy!
Geez, this is the itchiest!
Pascal!
Pascal, were have you gone!?
Pascal!!
Why did you go to that place
all by yourself for?
I was called.
You were called? By who?
I don't know.
I found a letter in my pocket
from some unknown person.
Do you still have that letter?
I threw it away!
What was written in the letter?
Onee-san?
"I will tell you how to
monopolize the inheritance."
What's that?
Was the one targeting
the inheritance not me, but you, Kotomi?
You're wrong!
I wouldn't consider such a thing.
However...
...whoever called me away
may be the one who killed Ryoji.
The clue to the culprit...
What's this 'clue'?
Your target is the inheritance!
Please wait, you two.
Inheritance, inheritance!
Dad's not even dead yet!
I'm sorry...
...that you had to see something so unseemly.
Man?
Bird.
"Curse."
"Betrayal."
It just needs one more piece to complete it.
In other words...
...there will definitely be
one more incident that occurs.
I'm absolutely determined to prevent that.
"Do you want to be the fourth person
to become a hayanie?"
"Who other than Kozaka-san
and Ryoji-san were taken as hayanie?"
"Jyugoya Police Substation"
Ah...
Good morning.
Come in.
Has something happened?
Um...
There's something I'd like you to tell me.
Huh?
At the God's Perch before all this, there was
someone else who was a hayanie, wasn't there?
Hit the nail, didn't I?
Leave!
Please answer me.
Ya...yer noisy!
It's when Tokyo people like you come...
...that things happen that bring no good!
Tokyo people?
By "Tokyo people,"
do you mean the Wakura-sans?
Could it be that Wakura-san had been
to this village previously?
We don't have ta tell ya nothin'!
Takekura-san.
Listen up!
Once that suspension bridge's repaired,
hurry and get out of here!
I'm sorry.
I was just a little interested in something.
Documentation on the history of the village...
Would anything here be helpful?
Yeah. Thank you.
"Jyugoya Village Town Hall"
For records on those who have died,
I guess I'd still have to go to Town Hall...
Ala?
Misa-san?
This is...
...a bronze mirror?
"I see."
"These were opposing mirrors..."
"...connected from back to back."
"Found at the Fobina ruins [name]"
"Man"
Man?
"Similarities between
the Mayan Civilization's Fobina Ruins..."
"...and Jyugoya Village."
"Mayan Civilization's Fobina Ruins."
"Monstrous Bird."
"Jyugoya Village."
"Otori."
"Light of the Sun."
"Reaching the pyramid."
"The bronze mirror on God's Perch."
"Resonance."
"Coming down from Heaven."
"Flying down from Heaven."
"Sacrifice... to God."
"Hayanie."
"Fobina Ruins"
"Underground water"?
"Jyugoya Village"
"The God's Perches are landmarks
for underground water?!"
"First."
"This is where Kozaka-san's death took place..."
"And here's Ryoji-san's."
"And here's where Kotomi-san flew..."
Konno Machiko.
"Konno Machiko
1986 death"
Ha! Don't come near!
This is a place where the Wakura
and those associated with them cannot come near!
Leave!
Are you saying that this death
is related somehow to Wakura-san?
Aren't you?
And just who was the one
that was a hayanie before?
Please answer me!
Just how much...
...do you know about
the legend of this village?
Long ago...
...it's said a giant Mozu bird
made a hayanie out of a person.
The bronze mirror in the shrine
resonates with the God's Perch...
...once every 300 years
to cause a solar total eclipse.
And that...
...lovers who exchange kisses
under the Perch...
...will never leave one another
their entire lives.
I see.
Is that everything about the legend?
Isn't there still something left hidden?
That's everything.
If you know the legend...
...then don't let yourself
be attacked by Otori-sama...
...and be quiet.
A person can't die from a legend.
Please tell me everything you know.
Too insistent!
Just before a murder occurs,
the sound of something creaking is heard.
Just what is that?
It's Otori-sama's wrathful cry.
You've realized it, haven't you?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm all better now.
Wakura-san, ever since your school days...
...it's said you've been investigating the Otori
legend and legends of giant birds, haven't you?
And?
Didn't you...
...also visit Jyugoya Village long ago?
What are you getting at?
That bronze mirror...
Could it be...
...that it's the true bronze mirror
from the Mozutobi Shrine?
Konno Machiko-san.
You knew her, didn't you?
And you know who the culprit is, don't you?
This is...
"Ran!"
"I see!"
I thought so.
"I know now what the trick was."
"Like I thought, he's the murderer..."
The people of the village are worried it'll
become dangerous if you come to the festival.
That's right! It's best not to come.
Is it against the law if I do come?
Huh?!
You outsiders, acting all great!
Outsiders?
Currently I'm the largest
landowner in this village.
Otori-sama...
...will make you his hayanie and...
Whatever you or anyone else says,
I will go to the festival.
Very well.
On that day, I will protect you.
I'll be under your care.
All of you, go home for today.
Hang on a second!
He'll cause trouble!
Kobayashi-san, you go on home, too.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
This murder case hasn't ended yet.
Because the culprit's primary goal...
...hasn't been achieved yet.
What is the culprit's goal?
"The Day of the Festival"
Somehow, this musical accompaniment
is rather weird.
Yeah.
Will this be okay!?
Don't worry. It's sure to work.
"Inner Sanctuary
God's Perch"
The village chief...
...and those attending him...
...approach!
Right now, I am the owner of this village.
Ohh!
Calm down. Calm down.
Otori-sama, calm down.
Calm down, calm down.
Calm down, Otori-sama.
Otori-sama, calm down. Calm down.
Calm down. Calm down. Otori-sama, calm down.
Calm down, calm down.
Otori-sama, calm down. Calm down...
Calm down. Calm down. Otori-sama, calm down.
Calm down, calm down.
No!
Wa... Wakura-san!
Wakura-san!
Huh? It's not!
Dad!
Indeed...
...encountering Otori-sama's curse
is just like an impossible crime.
You can't help but think this couldn't
possibly be the act of a human.
However...
...the culprit made use of that power...
...to make Kozaka-san and Ryoji-san...
...fly up onto the God's Perch where
they were then stabbed and killed.
Just like this.
When pressure is applied to water or air
in an airtight container...
...that pressure is transmitted to
every part of the fluid at the same strength...
...so such a device is utilizing
Pascal's principle.
Beneath this village, a network of
underground waterways have been stretched.
The culprit used that to commit murder.
First...
...water from the river is sidelined
into a hole and temporarily held there.
When the hole's lid is opened remotely,
the water flows down it all at once.
This creates a huge amount of air pressure.
This air pressure then spreads
through the waterway...
...springing up this slate.
That creaking sound you hear...
...is the sound of
the lid cover being opened.
The first victim was Kozaka-san, wasn't it?
But, the one the culprit
was aiming for that time was...
...Misa-san.
The culprit, his target being Misa-san...
...chose his timing when she was
standing on this slate to push the remote control.
However, his timing was slightly off...
...so it was Kozaka-san who became the victim.
Upon that failure, the culprit decided to
summon just his target alone.
"Where are you?"
Ryoji...
In the same way,
he then summoned his next target, Kotomi-san...
...but that crime ended in failure.
That was because there
wasn't enough air pressure.
The previous night,
Ran had stumbled over it...
...causing the slate to slip.
The culprit hadn't noticed that.
Lastly, the culprit targeted Wakura-san.
The moment that darkness fell,
the culprit pressed the remote switch.
However...
...that darkness...
...was a false solar eclipse
created by Ran and Sonoko.
The culprit had unknowingly
fallen into my trap.
The culprit...
...is you.
Police officer, Haji.
Wha... what's that?!
Why?
Eh? What evidence do you have?
This is the evidence.
Ow!
Is your hand okay?
Although you're a right-handed person...
...you protected the right hand
that Ran had kicked...
...and were using your left hand
to hold the screwdriver.
"Ah, good morning."
What you were fixing that time
wasn't the walkie-talkies...
...but the remote control.
The reason you were
attacking the Wakura family...
...was due to Konno Machko-san.
Her death is related to this, isn't it?
30 years ago...
...Machiko-san fell in love with Wakura-san...
...and she was the one
he promised eternal love to.
He betrayed my mother and abandoned her.
Mom believed in his oath...
...and waited and waited
and kept on waiting for him.
I thought so.
Policeman Haji...
...Machiko-san was
your true mother, wasn't she?
Around her meMōrial there were flowers
and Policeman Haji's footprints.
At the time of Machiko-san's death,
Haji would have been 4 or 5 years old.
To have a person die when
you're at such a young age...
...and yet come even now to pray for her...
...that would be unthinkable unless
it was anyone but your true mother.
You were really that boy then, weren't you?
25 years ago...
...Machiko suddenly appeared before me.
"Who is this child?"
She was with a small child.
"A relative's child."
"This is..."
"...the bronze mirror handed down
to the shrine that you wanted to see."
At the time, the business I had
was starting to take off...
...and had been picked up by the mass media.
I was under the impression Machiko
had come to extort money from me.
Mom didn't turn the bronze mirror
over to you because she wanted your money!
She just...
...wanted you...
...remember the vow of love
you had made to her.
My betrayed mother...
...was closely embracing
this bronze mirror when...
I am truly...
Truly very sorry.
How terrible.
All of the culprit's crimes...
...were to remind Wakura-san
of his betrayal of Machiko-san...
...and to take revenge for it.
It was my mistake...
...that caused all of this.
The loss of Ryoji...
The loss of Kozaka-kun...
And...
...that Machiko was left to die.
Having been in love during
the days of your youth...
...isn't a cause for blame.
However...
...it's said she was a woman
whose life was driven mad.
Your lover's feelings...
...were much too strong.
It...
...wasn't only Machiko's life.
I also messed up your life as well.
Are you...
Could it be you are mine and Machiko's...
I have no father.
I absolutely won't
acknowledge you as my father!
Policeman Haji!
I spoke to Wakura-san about my reasoning.
Wakura-san said...
"I don't want you to let him
commit any more crimes."
Saying so...
...he risked his life to cooperate with me.
Such a sad, lonely picture.
Policeman Haji.
For you...
...this crying woman was, you felt,
just like your mother, Machiko-san.
These two bronze mirrors, when back to back,
express the full details of the legend.
The bronze mirror Wakura-san was holding
contains the character for "man"...
...as the one who accomplished a betrayal.
On this bronze mirror,
this character perhaps stands for "woman."
This is the detailed account of a woman.
What do you mean?
Otori...
...is the incarnation of a woman
betrayed by her lover.
That's been handed down
generation to generation.
Long ago...
...though they had vowed and kissed
under the God's Perch...
...the young man abandoned the woman...
...and ran away.
For the woman...
...her passions turned into wings...
...and she became the huge, ugly Otori...
...to attack the man who had betrayed her.
The woman, cursed...
...ate the man and became the Otori.
Was the reason you wouldn't
explain all the details of the legend...
...because you wanted to
protect Policeman Haji?
I...
...took pity on this child...
...and raised him with my own hand.
So that's it.
So when you told the
Wakura family members to leave this village...
...it was because you didn't want Policeman Haji
repeating his crimes any more, wasn't it?
Mom...
Mom, I'm sorry.
After 25 years,
the true bronze mirror has returned.
Ah...
A total solar eclipse.
It's Machiko!
Machiko has come back as the birds!
A flock of birds?
Birds...
Did a flock of birds hide the sun?
That's incredibly mysterious.
Captain Megure?
How long have you been here?
We finally got the suspension bridge repaired.
I heard the entire story.
Well, good work, good work.
Seriously?
He was here...
Such a sad case, wasn't it?
Yeah.
Say, Ran.
Huh?
About what you said that time.
That time?
When we had fallen into that hole.
"I'm happy that we came."
"But..."
"...even if it hadn't been me..."
"...you would have gone out
to rescue anyone, wouldn't you?"
I...
Yeah.
...did it BECAUSE it was Ran.
I told you, it's Pascal!
A raccoon is called Rascal!
I've told you, this one's called Pascal!
Once I deliver him to that owner,
everything will be completely settled!
That'd be a trick!
It'd be impossible for that owner
to be tricked by this.
The main point is that it's the same breed!
It's totally different!
Mom! Dad!
Ran.
Where on earth have you two been?
This absurdity of a man here
said he had to catch a raccoon...
...so after searching the mountains
calling out, "Pascal, Pascal"...
...in the end what he got was...
...this.
This is what you've been doing all this time?
The entire time.
The main thing is they're similar, right?
Ah, so itchy.
Still... Pascal turned out to be a good tip.
Of course.
I knew that from the start.
That's why I kept on
telling you about Rascal.
You should be thanking me.
No, it's supposed to be "Pascal."
Wait! Don't leave me behind!
I thought I would help by
saying Rascal and Pascal.
Ah, he's running away. Hey!
I was surprised.
Sorry.
There can only be a single truth!
This Drama is Fictional.